



Date of birthNationalityGenderPlace of birth25-06-1984JordanianMaleSaudi arabia

Marital status LinkedIn

Married https://www.linkedin.com/in/fouadwtaha/

Willing to get a Job with a reputable organization, to gain a professional experience in the field of Enterprise resource planning (ERP), Human Resource Management System(HRMS), Management Information System (MIS), Manpower solutions or Information Technology (IT) sector and to enjoy working in a challenging and Rewarding job.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Management Information System

Al-Ahliyya Amman University, Amman/Jordan

Sep 2003 - Jan 2008

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior ERP Functional Consultant

Jul 2021 - Present

Tabadul, Riyadh/Saudi Arabia

- -Support End User and Business User for daily activities and work to enhance the System features to cover User requirements.
- -Seek out systems solutions that can be leveraged to meet business requirements.
- -Ensure successful deployments by designing, configuring, and testing to meet the Specific needs of Business
- -Review of the Deliverable to meet the requirements and to meet the Quality Standards.
- -Developing methods, techniques, architectures and standards for obtaining solutions.
- -Collaborating with business users to find alternatives and solutions to business challenges and Help Business users to use HCM in best way.
- -Coordinate with Technical team to direct and manage development from beginning to end on multiple simultaneous IT and ERP.
- -Implementation and User Training and manage all ERP activities.

Senior HCM Functional Consultant

Apr 2018 - Jun 2021

Solvait, Riyadh/Saudi Arabia

- -Microsoft Dynamics Implementation "365, AX" as LCS and Sure Step Methodology Pending On Customer Requirement Like, FRD, FDD, FRMD ...etc.
- -Outsource Functional Consultant on Semi -Government Company Support End User and Business User for daily activities and work to enhance the System features to cover User requirements.
- -Ensure successful deployments by designing, configuring, and testing to meet the Specific needs of Clients.
- -Review of the Deliverable to meet the requirements and to meet the Quality Standards.
- $\hbox{-Perform the Following on an engagement understand client business requirements, Configuration,}\\$

Demonstrate the configurations through the development of prototype systems, assist the client in Testing the solution.

- -Work with the client to help convert legacy data
- -Help client to use HCM in best way for each individual client
- -Ensure the client is reference able once the client is in production.

Share product knowledge with other consultants

- -Provide the Engagement Manager with status reports and keep them apprised of Overall Project status.
- -Implementation and User Training
- -I May participate in sales and proposal activities in addition to completing ongoing Team account responsibilities

AlfaPeople, Riyadh/Saudi Arabia

- -Worked on several large and Complex Dynamics AX and Dynamics365 projects "Private, Government sectors" in different industries implementations and Go-Lives.
- -Microsoft Dynamics Implementation "as Sure Step Methodology "Pending on Customer Requirement Like SOW, FRD, FDD etc.
- -Project Management under Sure Step Methodology.
- -Review of the Deliverable to meet the requirements and to meet the Quality Standards.
- -Data gathering during Diagnostics / Presales and provide HighLevel requirements document.
- -Presales and Proof of Concept development.
- -Implementation and User Training
- -Senior and Specialist in HR & Payroll and Manpower Modules –Full experience in HR & Payroll, Manpower in Saudi Arabia laws with successful Implementation.
- -Specialist and Good Knowledge in Financial Module Including (A/R, A/P, Bank, FA, and GL) with successful Implementation.
- -Excellent Knowledge & Support in Trade & Logistic Modules.
- -Microsoft Dynamics AX, D365 Administration (Security, End User Support

ERP Consultant AX & GP Jul 2008 - Feb 2014

InnoKAT(Innovation, Knowledge, and Advanced Technologies)., Riyadh/Saudi Arabia

Microsoft Dynamics (GP & AX) Implementation "as Sure Step Methodology "Pending on Customer Requirement Microsoft Dynamics Forum Modifier SQL (2000, 2005 & 2008). Data Base Maintenance Customization & Modify Reports on Crystal Reports and Reports Writer. Pre-Sale. Create Smart list using "Smartlist Builder" in GP. Microsoft Dynamics GP & AX Administration (Security, Field Level Security & End User Support) Specialist in Financial Module - with successful Implementation. Specialist in HR & Payroll Module (GP & AX) - with successful Implementation. Excellent Knowledge & Support in Sales and Purchasing-GP & Trade & Logistic-AX Modules.

Sales consultant Apr 2008 - Jun 2008

InnoKAT (Innovation, Knowledge, and Advanced Technologies), Riyadh/Saudi Arabia

Marketing Microsoft Dynamics, (Business Solutions is an innovative Enterprise Resource Planning system designed to deliver desktop access to business-critical information in a client/server environment). Contact with present customers, after-sales service, and all Sales consultant functions I have strong technical background Microsoft dynamics ERP January

System Admin (Help Disk)-Part Time

Jan 2007 - May 2007

Specialist Universal Networks, Amman/Jordan

Control all technical requirement/ support received from the client, like formatting, operatingsystems Installation (Microsoft 9x, XP, Microsoft server), systems hardware (PCs, NT, Printers) downloading major programs, and general system maintenance

LANGUAGES

English Native
Arabic Native

COURSES

Microsoft Dynamics™ GP 9.0 Financials (Score 84 / 100)

Managing Microsoft Dynamics Implementations "Sure Step" (Score 95 / 100)

What's New-Application in MS AX 2012 for Finance, Project Accounting and Case Management.

MB-300:MS Dynamics 365:Core Finance and Operations

Prepare for ITIL

Prepare for MB-330 "MS Dynamics 365 Exams "

Prepare for MB-700 "MS Dynamics 365 Exams "

SKILLS

Pre-salesExpertBusiness AnalysisExpertPower BIExpertSQLSkillful

Database tools such as power

Designer Intermediate
Crystal Report Expert

SPECIAL SKILLS AND ABILITIES

- -Strong interpersonal skills in communicating harmoniously with others and working with various nationalities.
- -Ability to initiate and maintain good relationship between company and clients.
- -Acquired the ability adaptable to any environment (i.e. country environment, culture, Market composition, & company environment etc.)

SPECIAL TRAINING

Willing to undergo any amount of special training necessary to adequately meet the continuing demands of any position.

UNIVERSITY MAJOR PROJECT

- Project Name: Hospital / Medical Management program
- It's a database linking sections of the hospital, recording the names of patients, doctors, nurses and those working in the hospital, generate & maintain the schedules for all the staff, arranged & accessible easily, the tables are linked together with key tables, the programs includes accounting for patients and staff, And added some modules for more security.

The Project has been programmed to Access 2003 and has been added macros, modules and VB code to be supporting the advantages new features.

TRAVEL

Willing to comply with all traveling requirements

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- -Valid Transferable Saudi Iqama
- -Valid Driving License

REFERENCES

References available on request.